savingstar.com 2014-07-02

# Privacy Policy | SavingStar

**Updated: October 15, 2013**

SavingStar, Inc. recognizes that your privacy is important, and we want to be transparent about the information we collect, how we share and use that information and what controls you have. SavingStar is in the business of operating, administering, and providing services to rewards programs to help consumers receive value back when they shop. This Privacy Policy applies to all information collected by SavingStar, Inc. and any corporate affiliates (collectively, “SavingStar”) for current and former consumers in connection with the SavingStar  Rewards Program offered on the SavingStar Website and mobile applications. (“SavingStar Rewards Program”). Wherever we provide examples of information in this Privacy Policy, the examples are not intended to be an exhaustive list.

We make available third party applications such as Facebook Connect and the SavingStar CashBack Toolbar, both of which may collect information about you and are further described below in the section below titled “Interaction with Third Party Websites and Third Party Applications and Services.”

We do not exercise control over any other websites or services made available to you through the SavingStar Rewards Program, such as those of our Participating Retailers. These sites and services may place their own cookies or other files on your computer, collect data or solicit information from you. We are not responsible for the actions or practices of these third parties. In addition, certain portions of the SavingStar Rewards Program, including sites, applications, programs, toolbars and utilities, may be operated by third parties, and your participation in those portions of SavingStar Rewards Program may be subject to additional privacy policies provided by SavingStar and/or the privacy policies of the third parties that operate them.

Please read this Privacy Policy carefully and [contact us](https://savingstar.com/contact)  if you have any questions or concerns. Click here for an explanation of Key Terms used in this Privacy Policy. ** **

**What information does SavingStar Collect?**

We may collect the following types of information:

**Information you provide**

We receive and store the information you enter on SavingStar Websites, mobile applications, or information you provide us in any other way, for example, by email or through correspondence. Click here to see examples of information you may provide us.

**Information about your purchases with Participating Retailers**

 We receive information about your purchases with Participating Retailers.

**Award information**

We will collect and maintain records to keep track of the Awards you earn.

**Information from cookies and other tracking technologies.**  

When you visit a SavingStar Website directly or through a mobile application, click on a banner advertisement, or open a SavingStar email, we or our third party service providers may send one or more cookies to your computer or other device. We use cookies to track information about your activities on the SavingStar Websites and mobile applications. We also use cookies to store your preferences and to allow you to remain logged in as you use our website.

We or our third party service providers may also use other similar technologies such as tracking pixels, tags or similar tools when you visit our website, open a SavingStar e-mail, or use our mobile applications.  These technologies can collect data regarding your operating system, browser type, device type, mobile device ID, screen resolution, IP address and other technical information, as well as navigation events and session information as you interact with our website or mobile applications. We use the information obtained from cookies and these other tracking technologies to help us understand how you use the SavingStar Websites or mobile applications and what products and services may be of interest to you and to enhance the value of the SavingStar Website.  We may combine this information with the Personal Information we have collected about you.

You can reset your browser to refuse all cookies or to indicate when a cookie is being sent. However, some features or services on our website or mobile applications may not function properly without cookies. For example, if you refuse cookies you will not be able to select Awards and link them to your loyalty card(s), earn awards for shopping on the SavingStar CashBack Mall, or use the SavingStar CashBack Toolbar.

**Log and other information**

When you access a SavingStar Website, email, advertisement, or other content served by the SavingStar Website or SavingStar mobile applications, our servers automatically record information that your browser sends whenever you visit a website. These server logs typically include your web request, Internet Protocol address, browser type, browser language, the date and time of your request, your location if you allow your internet service provider or mobile device provider to send it to us, and one or more cookies that may uniquely identify your browser or Account (s) to us. Other actions, such as interactions with advertisements, may also be included in our server logs. During some visits to our websites we may use software tools such as JavaScript to measure and collect session information, including page response times, download errors, length of visits to certain pages, page interaction information (such as scrolling, clicks, and mouse-overs), and methods used to browse away from the page. Please be aware that in some cases your internet protocol address could be used to determine your general location.

**Interaction with Third Party Websites and Third Party Applications.**

You can use features such as Facebook Connect to connect your social media sites to the SavingStar Website and share information about us. If you use a social media website in connection with the SavingStar Website, we may collect your user name and other profile information. Click here for more information.  We are not responsible for the actions or practices of third party social media websites or their privacy policies.

SavingStar may host or frame a webpage or webpages within a third party website. Under those circumstances, this Privacy Policy will only apply to information about you that SavingStar collects from the webpage or webpages that SavingStar hosts or “frames “on the third party website, and SavingStar’s Privacy Policy shall not apply to the rest of the third party website which should have its own privacy policy and data collection practices. We are not responsible for the actions or practices of third party websites or their privacy policies.

We also may make third party applications available for you to download. The information collected by third party application providers is governed by their privacy policies unless otherwise stated. For example, the SavingStar CashBack Toolbar is provided by a third party on SavingStar’s behalf and is subject to a separate privacy policy which can be accessed from the webpage where you have the option to install the SavingStar CashBack Toolbar application. To learn more about the information collected by the SavingStar CashBack Toolbar, including how it may be used and shared, please read the SavingStar CashBack Toolbar Privacy Statement.

**Information from other sources**  
We may receive information about you from various sources. Click here to see examples of information we may receive from other sources.

**How does SavingStar use my information?**

**To manage your Account(s)**

We use the information we collect to manage your Account(s). For example, we use the information you provide us and the purchase information we collect to track, process, post and fulfill Awards you earn and to provide customer service.

**To develop, evaluate, improve and deliver our products and services for you**

We use the information we collect to develop, evaluate, improve and deliver our product and services, and the products and services of, Award Providers, Participating Retailers, or others. For example, if we learn from the information we collect that certain categories of products are highly valuable to Registered Users; we may encourage Award Providers to offer more Awards in those categories which would make our products and services more valuable to Registered Users.

**To deliver personalized advertisements and other information to you**

We may use the information we collect to deliver advertisements about our products and services, and/or the products and services of, Award Providers, Participating Retailers, or others on our websites, other websites, mobile applications, or in other marketing channels. For example, we may use the purchase information we collect about you because of your participation in the SavingStar Rewards Program to deliver to you, via one or more of those channels, advertisements that we, or the parties whose products or services we are promoting, think may be of interest to you.

We also may engage third party advertising networks to deliver these advertisements.  For example, we use Remarketing with Google Analytics to advertise online.  Third-party vendors including Google show SavingStar ads on sites across the internet.  SavingStar and third-party vendors, including Google, use first-party cookies (such as the Google Analytics cookie) and third-party cookies (such as the DoubleClick cookie) together to inform, optimize, and serve ads based on someone’s past visits to your website. These networks use cookies and similar technologies to personalize the advertising content you see and to measure the effectiveness of the advertisements they deliver. These companies are authorized to use the information we provide and they collect when you navigate to a website within the ad network to provide this service to us. Each of the advertising networks we work with is a member of the Network Advertising Initiative. If you prefer not to receive advertisements from the advertising networks we work with as you surf the Internet, you may opt-out by clicking on this opt-out link [**http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp**](http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp)

Please allow up to 10 days for the opt-out to take effect. Please also note that in order for the opt-out to work your browser must be set to accept third party cookies. Furthermore, if you use a different computer, change web browsers or delete the opt-out cookie, you will need to perform the opt-out task again.

**Fulfill legal and regulatory requirements**

We may use the information we collect to comply with federal, state, or other applicable laws and regulations.

**Protect the rights or property of SavingStar or our Registered Users**

We also may use the information we collect to the extent we believe it is necessary or appropriate to enforce or apply our rights under our agreements with Registered Users, and/or to protect the rights, property or safety of SavingStar, our Registered Users, and others.

**Combine Personal and Nonpersonal Information**

We may combine any Personal Information we have about you with Nonpersonal Information we have about you.

**How does SavingStar share your information?**

**Personal Information**

We may share Personal Information with our corporate affiliates that either are subject to this Privacy Policy or follow practices at least as protective as those described in this Privacy Policy with respect to the Personal Information we share with them.

**Contests, sweepstakes and surveys**

We may promote or offer contests, sweepstakes, similar promotional offers or surveys that may be co-sponsored by SavingStar and one or more other companies, or may be sponsored by companies other than SavingStar. Some or all of the Personal Information collected through these offers or surveys may be shared with the sponsor(s) or other companies indicated on the entry form, in the governing rules or on the survey, as applicable.

**Agents and service providers**

We engage other companies and individuals to perform certain services and functions on our behalf. For example, we may engage third parties to send email and postal mail, analyze data, provide marketing services, process applications, provide search results and links (including paid listings and links), and provide customer service. We contractually obligate these service providers to access and use the Personal Information we make available to them only as needed to perform services for us and for no other purposes.

**Information we share with nonaffiliated third parties as permitted by law:**

We reserve the right to disclose Personal Information to the extent permitted by applicable law, for example: Business transfers: If there is a change of control in SavingStar’s business (whether by merger, sale, or otherwise), your Personal Information could be sold as part of that transaction and could be used by the purchaser. We will notify you by email to the email address we have on file for your Account if your Personal Information will become subject to a different privacy policy after the transaction.

**Protection of SavingStar and others:**

We may disclose Personal Information about you to third parties when we believe such disclosure is appropriate to comply with a legal requirement, such as a law, regulation, court order, subpoena or search warrant, or in the course of a legal proceeding. We may also disclose Personal Information as we believe appropriate to enforce or apply our rights under our agreements with Registered Users, to protect the rights, property or safety of SavingStar, our Registered Users and others, including exchanging information for fraud protection and credit risk reduction.

**With your consent:**

In addition to the above, we may share Personal Information about you with others to the extent you consent to such sharing. For example, we may share your email with a Participating Retailer or Awards Provider but only after you have provided consent.

**Nonpersonal Information**

We may provide Nonpersonal Information about you to Award Providers, Participating Retailers, and other third parties for marketing, analysis and other purposes. For example, your purchase information may be aggregated with the purchase information of other Registered Users and analyzed to evaluate the effectiveness of certain award offers or advertisements, and the results of that analysis may be shared with Award Providers, Participating Retailers, or other third parties.

**Security of Your Personal Information**

SavingStar is committed to earning and keeping your trust. We understand the need for your Personal Information to remain secure and private, and we have implemented reasonable security practices and procedures designed to safeguard your information in accordance with this Privacy Policy. Only SavingStar employees and service providers who need to use it as part of their jobs are authorized to have access to your Personal Information.  While we do work hard to protect your privacy, no method of security is 100% effective and we cannot be responsible for the actions of those who may gain unauthorized access to your Personal Information.  SavingStar makes no warranties, express, implied or otherwise as to the ultimate effectiveness of these reasonable and appropriate safeguards.

Please remember that you also play a valuable part in data security. You should never share your Rewards Program password, if applicable, with anyone. If you feel your password has been compromised, you should change it immediately. After you have finished using our website(s), you should log out of your Account and exit your browser so that no unauthorized persons can use our website under your name or Account. You should use particular caution if you are using a shared or public computer.

**Online Forums**

Please note that information you voluntarily include in bulletin boards, chat rooms and other online forums we may offer may be viewed and used by anyone with access to those forums. SavingStar is unable to control and is not responsible for any use of such information.

We may provide you the ability to log on to SavingStar Websites or mobile applications using third party sign-in services such as Facebook Connect or an Open ID provider. These services will authenticate your identity and may provide you the option to share certain Personal Information with us such as the name of the social media website, your User ID, your public profile which may include, for example your contact list, including their User IDs,  your name and email address to pre-populate our sign up form. Social Media website services, like Facebook Connect, give you the option to post information about your activities on our website(s) to your profile page to share with others within your network. If you tell your social media contacts about us, we will see and may store that contact’s user ID.

If you choose to link your social media profile to the SavingStar Website, we receive information which may include your user ID, the pages you were visiting when you chose to link to us or otherwise bring us to the attention of your contacts, and other information about offers in which you are interested. We may also collect any profile information that you share with everyone. 

To review and manage the privacy settings for your social media account, including the information you share with everyone, you should refer to the privacy settings for your social media account and that website’s privacy policy – we have no control and are not responsible for what profile information is shared or made public by other third party websites, including social media websites.

**Collection of Information from Children**

None of our products or services is intended for use or purchase by children. Accordingly, SavingStar does not knowingly collect, either online or offline, information from children under the age of 13. If you believe that we might have any information from a child under age 13, please [contact us](https://savingstar.com/contact).

**What Information Can I Access?**

You may access and update information stored in your Account profile(s) by visitingSavingStar.com. Please keep your contact and other Account information up-to-date. Doing so helps ensure that your Awards are properly tracked and that we can communicate with you as necessary.

**What About Links to Other Websites?**

Through our various online offerings, we may provide links to third-party websites such as the websites of Participating Retailers, and Award Providers. Each of these websites may have separate privacy and different data collection practices from SavingStar, and we are not responsible for the actions or practices of these third parties, or for the content on these sites. We encourage you to review the privacy policies of third party websites.

**What about Do Not Track Requests**

Currently, SavingStar does not take any action in response to “do not track” signals or other similar mechanisms.

**Changes to this Privacy Policy**

Please note that this Privacy Policy may change from time to time so please review it frequently. We will post any Privacy Policy changes on this page and, if the changes are significant, we will provide a more prominent notice by means of a notice on the SavingStar Website homepage or by email to the email address we have on file in your Account. Each version of this Privacy Policy will be identified at the top of the Privacy Policy by its effective date, and we will also keep prior versions of this Privacy Policy in an archive for your review.

**Key Terms**

**Account**

An “Account” is an account you establish with a Rewards Program.

**Affiliate Stores and Affiliate Networks**  
****

We and some of our Participating Retailers participate in certain affiliate marketing networks, otherwise known as affiliate networks. An affiliate network acts as an intermediary between SavingStar and our Participating Retailers. Participating in an affiliate network enables SavingStar to offer Awards to Registered Users.

The affiliate networks we participate in and our Participating Retailers may share with us data about you and your purchases with the Participating Retailers, which may include the amount of your order, your e-mail address, the time and date of the transaction, the order number, the product(s) purchased, and a unique customer ID. This information allows us to properly assign you Awards. Affiliate networks may also share with us the identity of the website you visited prior to signing up as a Registered User. This information allows us to compensate the appropriate website.  For information about the privacy practices of these Participating Retailers and affiliate networks, you should consult their respective privacy policies. We do not have any control over how Participating Retailers or affiliate networks treat the Personal Information they collect from you. We are not responsible for the actions or policies of any Participating Retailers’ sites, including web pages from a Participating Retailers’ site that are “framed” within a SavingStar Website or mobile application.

**Awards**

“Awards” are the discounts, cash rebates, other cash Awards, points, miles and/or other awards that Award Providers offer you as a Registered User of a Rewards Program.

**Award Providers**

An “Award Provider” is a company or other entity that offers you an award if you make an eligible purchase of the entity’s products or services through one or more Rewards Programs. Award Providers can be consumer packaged goods manufacturers, grocery stores, drug stores, online retailers, or other entities.

**Cookies**

A “cookie” is a small file containing a string of characters that is sent to your computer when you visit a website. When you visit the website again, the cookie allows that site to recognize your browser. Cookies may store user preferences and other information. ** **

**Information from other sources**

We may obtain information about you from third parties including Award Providers, our affiliates, public sources, and others. This information could include, among other things, information about your purchases with information about your transactions and account activity with us, our affiliates and others, your location if you allow your mobile device provider to send it to us, your mobile device ID, publicly available demographic data, and information needed to comply with regulatory requirements and information designed to ensure the accuracy of data, better understand your likely interests, and/or prevent fraud.

Other examples of information we may receive from other sources include updated delivery and address information from third parties, which we use to correct our records and deliver you communications, and demographic information from data collection companies and others.

**Information you provide**

In connection with your participation in the SavingStar Rewards Program, you may provide us information such as your name, mailing address, email address, phone number, username, password, and your grocery or drugstore loyalty card numbers so that we may track your qualified purchases with Award Providers. You also provide us information when you navigate our websites, use our mobile applications activate Award offers, open and/or respond to our emails, participate in a contest or questionnaire, or communicate with us by phone, e-mail, or otherwise. 

In connection with certain promotions, we may offer you credits toward Awards in exchange for your taking certain actions.  For example, you may receive credit toward an Award for watching a video or for sharing, or consenting to SavingStar’s sharing, your email address with a Participating Retailer, consumer packaged goods manufacturer, or other third party. 

If you give SavingStar your location, for example, when you use a SavingStar mobile application, we may use and store that information to provide you with location-based information or messaging, including, for example, offers or advertising. Many mobile devices operating systems are designed to automatically request your permission to use location.

**Nonpersonal Information**

“Nonpersonal Information” is any information about you that is not Personal Information.

**Participating Retailers**

“Participating Retailers” are retailers and other entities that sell products and services for which Award Providers offer Awards. Participating Retailers agree to provide or make available to us certain purchase information so that we may track Awards. A Participating Retailer can also be an Award Provider.

**Personal Information**

“Personal Information” is information that personally identifies you to the person or entity that is in possession of such information.

**Registered User**

A “Registered User” is an individual or entity that registers to participate in the SavingStar Rewards Program to earn Awards. 

**SavingStar Website or our website**  

A “SavingStar Website”, which may also be referred to as “our website”, is any website SavingStar hosts or otherwise operates.  It does not include third party websites.

**Unsubscribe**

Registered Users may control their email communication preferences on the “My Account” webpage of our website.  To unsubscribe from all future marketing email, click the unsubscribe link in the welcome email or any subsequent email from SavingStar. You may also contact SavingStar by email, or write or call SavingStar at:

SavingStar  
400 Totten Pond Rd Suite 300  
Waltham, MA 02451  
800.618.3893

## SavingStar Cashback Toolbar Privacy Statement

Last Updated: October 15, 2013

The SavingStar Cashback Toolbar is a web browser software application (the “Toolbar”), which is provided by Rakuten Loyalty, a third party toolbar provider (“RLO”). You should **read the entire SavingStar Cashback Toolbar Privacy Statement** , which follows, before downloading the Toolbar. If you do not accept this SavingStar Cashback Toolbar Privacy Statement, do not install or use the Toolbar or any of its features.

The  [Rakuten Technology Privacy Policy](http://rakutenloyalty.com/legal-technology-privacy-policy/) also provides information about the collection and use of information by the Toolbar. In the event of a conflict between this Privacy Statement and the Rakuten Technology Privacy Policy, this Privacy Statement will govern.  Please note that SavingStar is not responsible for the privacy practices of RLO and that RLO is not responsible for the privacy practices of SavingsStar.

**Relationship between SavingStar Privacy Statement and the Toolbar Privacy Statement**

1 .   **SavingStar Privacy Statement and the Toolbar Privacy Statement**

The [SavingStar Privacy Statement ](https://savingstar.com/blog/privacy-policy/)describes the types of personal information we obtain about you in connection with the SavingStar Rewards Program generally, and how we use and share that information, including information obtained when you use the Toolbar. This Toolbar Privacy Statement supplements the [SavingStar Privacy Statement](https://savingstar.com/blog/privacy-policy/) and describes the types of personal and other information we may obtain about you and your computer and browser if you install the Toolbar on your computer, and how we use and share that information. In the event of any inconsistency between the SavingStar Privacy Statement and this Toolbar Privacy Statement, this Toolbar Privacy Statement will govern. If you install and/or use the Toolbar, this Toolbar Privacy Statement applies to you. This Toolbar Privacy Statement may change from time to time, so you should check back frequently for any updates. 

2 .   **Information Collected by the Toolbar**

**a. General**

If you install and/or use the Toolbar with respect to an internet browser on your computer, the the Toolbar will collect certain information from your computer when the browser is running. As described more fully in this Toolbar Privacy Statement, this information is collected for a number of reasons, including, without limitation, to help us improve the Toolbar features and functionality, to provide you with your search results, to identify SavingStar partner websites to you, to enable us to process cash back earned by a SavingStar registered user when making an eligible online purchase, application or other transaction at a SavingStar partner website, and to help us understand how often individual SavingStar partner websites are visited.

In addition, the search terms and criteria (“search criteria”) that you may submit in the Toolbar search box or other search boxes that are interconnected with the search functionality in the toolbar, as well as other information, is collected by the Toolbar application and transmitted to RLO and the Toolbar search provider (currently, Yahoo!) (the ”Search Provider”). The transmissions of search criteria are sent unencrypted over the public Internet, so please use caution when including any search terms or other criteria so that they do not include any personal or other sensitive information. Please see Section 2.d and Section 5 for more information. 

b .   **When you install the Toolbar,** **the** **Toolbar will collect and store on your computer a unique ID (the “SavingStar ID”) and a different unique ID is also assigned to your Toolbar (the “Toolbar ID”) and stored on your computer, both of which may identify you personally to SavingStar.**  

When you install the Toolbar, the Toolbar will collect and store on your computer a unique ID (the “SavingStar ID”). In addition, when you install the Toolbar, a different unique ID is assigned to your Toolbar (the “Toolbar ID”) and stored on your computer. SavingStar can use the SavingStar ID and/or the Toolbar ID to identify you personally. RLO cannot use the SavingStar ID or the Toolbar ID to identify you personally, but may have information from another source which would allow it to identify you personally.

In order for you to be able to realize all the benefits of the Toolbar, your browser has to be set to accept cookies. If your browser is set not to accept cookies, SavingStar cannot reward you for eligible online purchases. You should be aware that even if your browser is set not to accept cookies when you install the Toolbar, SavingStar, RLO and the Search Provider may continue to collect search-related information described in this Toolbar Privacy Statement. By not accepting cookies or by clearing your cookies, you will not be uninstalling or disabling the Toolbar. To see how to uninstall the Toolbar, [click here](https://savingstar.com/blog/frequently-asked-questions/#uninstall_toolbar).

c.   **The** **Toolbar collects and transmits information about your Internet browser, your Installation of the Toolbar and your** ******Toolbar** **settings to improve the product and help you get the most out of it.**  

i.  When you first install the Toolbar, and after that whenever you update or uninstall the Toolbar, open a web browser session that includes the Toolbar, change your Toolbar settings, perform similar activities or otherwise, the Toolbar collects and transmits to SavingStar and RLO certain information about your Internet browser and your Toolbar settings. This information, which we call “Event Information,” includes (i) your SavingStar ID and Toolbar ID, (ii) your computer’s IP address, location, operating system, the Internet browser (including the version and subversion) you are using (e.g., Internet Explorer or Safari), product information about your Toolbar and its settings, and the URL of the website from which you came (if any) and the date and time of the visit and its duration. SavingStar can use the SavingStar ID and/or Toolbar ID to identify you personally. RLO, however, cannot use the SavingStar ID or the Toolbar ID to identify you personally, but may have information from another source which would allow it to personally identify you.

We use Event Information for several purposes, such as to understand which the Toolbar features users like and which features could benefit from improvement, based on how the features are used, and to diagnose and address technical issues with the Toolbar.

ii.  The Toolbar collects and provides to such website information about your installation of the Toolbar and your Toolbar settings. We call this information “Header Information” and it includes the Toolbar version installed on your computer along with information about your Toolbar settings. It also includes your SavingStar ID and Toolbar ID. We use this Header Information to improve your Toolbar experience, which may include suggesting ways in which you may optimize your use of the Toolbar. Based on your Header Information, we may also send you messages to suggest ways in which you may better use the Toolbar, or may prompt you to upgrade your Toolbar to a newer version if you are using an older version.

d .   **Toolbar collects and transmits all search criteria you may submit in the** ******Toolbar search box and, in certain instances, in any browser search boxes or otherwise if the browser defaults to a search based on your action.**

The Toolbar collects and transmits all search criteria you may submit in the Toolbar search box, along with the Event Information to SavingStar, RLO and the Search Provider. If you accept SavingStar Search as your browser’s default search provider (through the option provided on the Toolbar installation page), then the Toolbar also collects and transmits all search criteria you may submit in any browser search boxes or otherwise if the browser defaults to a search based on your action (for example, if you type in an invalid website URL and the browser conducts a search to find websites that come close to matching the website URL you entered), along with the Event Information.  

These search criteria and Event Information will be transmitted unencrypted over the public Internet to RLO and the Search Provider.  All such search criteria you enter, along with the Event Information, may be used and/or disclosed by the Search Provider to provide the search results and as otherwise described in the Search Provider’s privacy policy with respect to its search services. 

Accordingly, you should use caution not to include in any search criteria any personal or other sensitive information, such as any financial or health information, since such information would be collected by RLO via the Toolbar and would be transmitted to, the Search Provider without any encryption or similar security.   **SavingStar, RLO and the Search Provider do not have any obligation to maintain this information in any confidential or secure manner, and you should not have any expectation to the contrary.**  

 e .   **Toolbar collects your search results.**

The Toolbar collects and transmits the search results from searches conducted through the Toolbar and any Toolbar compatible search engine so that the Toolbar may identify and highlight SavingStar partners in the search results.

f .   **When you visit a website (regardless of whether you access such website via a Toolbar search), the Toolbar will review that website URL to determine if it is a SavingStar partner website. The** ******Toolbar collects and transmits information to let us know when you visit SavingStar partner websites and when additional Toolbar notifications are presented to you. This information may be associated with your SavingStar ID and/or Toolbar ID.**

When you visit a website (regardless of whether you access such website via a Toolbar search), the Toolbar will review that website URL to determine if it is a SavingStar partner website.

         When you visit a website:

  * The URL of the web page as well as the Event Information will be collected, processed and transmitted to SavingStar and RLO by the Toolbar in order to alert you to what steps you need to take, if any, to activate the SavingStar cash back rewards for eligible purchases, applications or other transactions made on that SavingStar partner website and to process cash back earned by SavingStar registered users. This information is also used to help us understand how often individual SavingStar partner websites are visited so that we may optimize your use of the Toolbar, which may include presenting cash back and other opportunities to you based on this information. The Toolbar may also provide notifications to you that suggest ways that you can get the most out of the Toolbar. These notifications may be shown to you based on your Toolbar settings and other information we learn about you. The Toolbar collects and transmits to SavingStar and RLO information about the notifications delivered to you. We also may collect information about your interaction with those suggestions, such as whether or not you clicked on a link presented in a notification. 

  * If you are a SavingStar registered user, you will be identified to the SavingStar partner as a SavingStar registered user via the SavingStar ID. The SavingStar partner cannot use the SavingStar ID to identify you personally, but may have information from another source (for example, if you provide your contact information in connection with your online purchases, applications or other transactions at the SavingStar partner’s website or during any customer service process) which would allow it to personally identify you.

  * SavingStar receives information about your online purchases, applications or other transactions at SavingStar partner websites through one or more third party tracking agents that track purchases for a network of participating online merchants (“Affiliate Network”). The Affiliate Networks place “cookies” on your computer or hard drive. These cookies are strings of text that are sent to your computer that enable SavingStar to process cash back earned by a SavingStar registered user when making an eligible online purchase, application or other transaction with this SavingStar partner. In the event you make an online purchase, application or other transaction with the SavingStar partner, including through a secure session, SavingStar will receive information about your online purchase, application or transaction, including financial or health information if applicable to the transaction.

g .   **The Toolbar collects and transmits information about whether and how you interact with the Toolbar, and this information may be associated with your SavingStar ID and/or Toolbar ID.**  

The Toolbar collects and transmits to SavingStar and RLO information about what you click on in the Toolbar’s settings menu or on any of the icons in the toolbar. We use this information to provide the Toolbar to you, to improve the Toolbar and its features, and to improve your Toolbar experience. For example, we may show you notifications to suggest ways in which you may better use the Toolbar.

3 .   **Information collected and transmitted by the** ******Toolbar is used for a variety of purposes**

SavingStar may use the information collected and transmitted by the Toolbar and received by SavingStar to develop, offer, deliver, operate and improve the SavingStar website, services, and applications; for its own data analytical purposes; to understand how often partner websites are visited; to offer products and services of our affiliates, participating companies, marketing partners and other companies; to process transactions in your accounts; to fulfill legal and regulatory requirements; and as otherwise permitted by applicable law. For example, we use the information to:

  * Help us maintain and operate the Toolbar.
  * Help us provide you with your search results.
  * Help us better understand how users use the Toolbar, which helps us improve its features and functionality.
  * Help us understand how often individual SavingStar partner websites are visited.
  * Help us understand how you navigate the SavingStar website and use the SavingStar service.      
  * Help you optimize your use of the Toolbar.
  * Alert you to what steps you need to take, if any, to activate the SavingStar cash back rewards for eligible purchases, applications or other transactions made on a SavingStar partner website and to accurately credit cash back earned by SavingStar registered users for eligible purchases, applications or other transactions made on a SavingStar partner website.
  * Help us present cash back opportunities and other content to you in an effort to create a personally relevant experience. For example, we may use information about the SavingStar partner websites you visit to provide you special offers. SavingStar may also combine this information with personally identifiable information SavingStar may separately have about you as a SavingStar registered user, such as your individual transaction information, to assist with presenting offers to you.
  * Help us conduct marketing analysis, including helping us formulate and predict responses to various marketing campaigns, and to deliver and help determine the effectiveness of various marketing campaigns.
  * Help us support you when you contact SavingStar Customer Care.

Based on your Toolbar settings, information about the notifications delivered to you collected and transmitted by the Toolbar to SavingStar and RLO, and other information we learn about you, the Toolbar may also provide notifications to you that suggest ways that you can get the most out of the Toolbar and to deliver personalized offers. We also may collect information about your interaction with those suggestions, such as whether or not you clicked on a link presented in a notification.

4 .   **How Collected Information is Shared**

The Toolbar generally collects and transmits the information described in this Toolbar Privacy Statement to RLO (and as described, the Search Provider), which uses the information collected and transmitted by the Toolbar to help us provide services to you.

RLO may also use non-personally identifiable information collected and transmitted by the Toolbar for its internal data analytical purposes and may share such information with SavingStar.

As described above in Section 2.d, the Toolbar also transmits your search criteria and Event Information to the Search Provider.  The Search Provider may use and/or disclose such information to provide the search results and as otherwise described in its privacy policy. Neither SavingStar nor RLO has control over the Search Provider or its privacy practices. Please see the Search Provider’s applicable privacy policy for more information.  

SavingStar may share non-personally identifiable information collected by the Toolbar with unaffiliated third parties, such as our partners, service providers and the Affiliate Networks. For example, we may share such non-personally identifiable information with our partner companies to formulate, predict responses to, deliver and determine the effectiveness or value of various savings or other opportunities. We may also provide aggregated, non-personally identifiable information about the Toolbar users to these third parties for audit, marketing and other purposes.

SavingStar may share information with its affiliates, and as otherwise required or permitted by applicable law in accordance with the [SavingStar Privacy Statement](https://savingstar.com/blog/privacy-policy/).[  
](https://lty.s.upromise.com/member/aboutus/privacy.do)

5 .   **Security and Encryption**  

The privacy and security of any information collected and transmitted by the Toolbar is very important to us. SavingStar uses the following features and technologies to help safeguard your information:

  * Encrypted Transmission. Except as stated in the below, SavingStar requires RLO to cause the Toolbar to transmit Event Information, Header Information, any other information collected by the Toolbar, and web service calls (such as those required to display account balance or deals) using encryption; provided however, that all information collected and transmitted by the Toolbar to the Search Provider is transmitted without encryption. Please see Section 2.d for more information.

  * Restricted Access. SavingStar has implemented policies and procedures designed to protect against unauthorized access to or unauthorized disclosure of data collected by the Toolbar.

If you are using a shared or public computer and do not wish to have your  information seen by other users, you should always log out of your account when finished.

6 .   **Uninstalling the Toolbar**

You may uninstall the Toolbar at any time and with no limitations, using the standard uninstall procedures offered with your computer’s operating system and/or or your internet browser. In general, if you are using a Windows operating systems, you may uninstall the Toolbar from your Internet Explorer via the “Add or Remove Programs” feature in your Control Panel; and if you are using Firefox as your internet browser, the Toolbar may be uninstalled via the “Tools” menu inside the browser.  As the features for browsers and operating systems changes from time to time, the foregoing steps may need to change slightly to conform to these changes.  Therefore, at the time of your uninstallation, please refer to the standard uninstall procedures offered with your computer’s operating system or your internet browser for the latest instructions regarding uninstallation.

When you uninstall the Toolbar, Event Information for the uninstall event will be transmitted to RLO and to SavingStar. If you need additional assistance, please contact [SavingStar Customer Service](https://savingstar.com/contact/new).

7 .   **Use of Information after Uninstalling**

Please note that SavingStar, RLO and the Search Provider may continue to use information collected from your Toolbar which was collected prior to your uninstallation of the Toolbar. In the case of SavingStar and RLO, all such information remains subject to the Toolbar Privacy Statement in effect at the time of uninstallation. In the case of the Search provider, please refer to their privacy policy for more information.
